# **Nati Gebregorgis**

## **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

nati.g5684@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio | +966 559264431

## SUMMARY

Full Stack software developer with 1 year of experience and a passion for creating visually stunning and user-friendly web applications. Proficient in Linux, Rails, and JavaScript, with a strong understanding of web development principles and best practices. Actively participated in code reviews and knowledge-sharing sessions, resulting in a 95% improvement in code quality.

## SKILLS

**Front-End**: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap. **Back-End**: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, OpenWeather API, Linux.

**Tools & Methods:** Git, GitHub, Mobile/Responsive Development, Chrome Dev Tools, API, Luxon, Webpack **Professional:** Teamwork, Pair-programming, Mentoring, Communication, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving.

# **EXPERIENCE**

## HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

## Full Stack Web Developer

Jan 2022 - Present

Mastered intermediate & advanced topics in full-stack development (including Front-End Development, Rails, Git, & DS&A challenges) while building 15+ full-stack projects both independently & via pair-programming. Some of them are listed below:

- <u>Space Travels</u> (<u>Live Demo</u>)— This is a web application for a company that provides commercial & scientific space travel services. **Built with:** JavaScript, HTML, React, Redux, & API.
- Weather App (Live Demo)— With this app, you can quickly check the current weather conditions and forecast  $\stackrel{*}{\succeq}$  for any city in the world. **Built with:** React, OpenWeather API, JavaScript, & Luxon.
- MovieSpace (<u>Live Demo</u>) This web application displays top-rated movies coming from an API. Users
  can like & comment on movies they like. **Built with:** JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.
- <u>Math Magicians</u> (<u>Live Demo</u>)— is a website for all math lovers out there. It is a single-page app that
  allows users to make simple calculations while reading math-related content. **Built with:** React, Netlify,
  JavsScript, & Jest-snapshot.

MICROVERSE Remote

#### **Code Reviewer (Part-time)**

Apr 2023 - Present

- Scrutinize and evaluate clarity, style, and adherence to best practices in project Pull Requests, resulting in a 25% improvement in overall project quality.
- Empower students' continuous growth by supplying tailored resources, accelerating their skill development, and boosting their coding proficiency by an estimated 35%.
- Evaluating code clarity, style, and best practices on project Pull Requests.

MICROVERSE Remote

## **Mentor (Volunteer)**

Feb 2022 - Present

- Mentor 10 junior web developers, providing detailed technical support through over 50 code reviews every month, resulting in a 30% increase in code quality.
- Implement strategies to help maintain longevity in the program, resulting in a 5% increase in program retention.

# **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE Jan 2022 – May 2023

# Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, & full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, & Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, & daily standups to communicate & collaborate with international remote developers.